Dylan LaMott

Experienced Remote Software developer with a strong focus in the Java programming language. My current role is a, Java Software Developer, responsible for creating and maintaining applications that automate the provisioning of users for a competitive company.

Contact information

Phone: 336-287-0002

Portfolio website:

https://portfolio-dlamott.vercel.app/

GitHub:

https://github.com/DLaMott

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/dylan-lamott-b39b472 00/

Skills: Java, Python, Swift, AWS, JavaScript, MySQL, SQLite, Kubernetes, HTML, CSS, Terraform, Apache, Windows OS, Mac OS, Linux

Education

Guilford Technical Community College

Jamestown, NC 2020 – 2022

Location: Advance, NC

A.S. Computer Programming

GPA: 4.0

Certifications
Test Out PC Pro

8/20

Certified by: Test Out

Java

December 10, 2021

Certified by: Guilford Technical community college

Computer Tech Integration

May 07, 2021

Certified by: Guilford Technical community college

Open-source contributions:

QuestDB: An open source database used by Yahoo, TQS, Turk telecom, and more. Find the company website here: https://questdb.io/

QuestDB Contribution 1: Link to accepted and merged PR: https://github.com/questdb/questdb/pull/1909

• The resolved issue was to fix long numeric overflow when utilizing nanoseconds to determine thread latch wait time. Previous code had incorrect method usage and incorrect data comparison.

QuestDB Contribution 2: Link to accepted and merged PR: https://github.com/questdb/pull/1998

- QuestDB needed a method to track property keys for server configuration files at start-up. Upon taking this issue, I realized the current method to load these property keys was using string literals. Over three hundred lines had lengthy string literal property keys which can be vulnerable to error.
- To promote code reusability, type safety, and reduce errors I created an enum storing property keys. Using my new enum I was able to replace the majority of the code within their server configuration driver.
- I added a test and property key validation method. The added method prevents the server from running if users enter incorrect keys in the server configuration file. The method will throw a server configuration exception and display the invalid line. Overall, this project was merged with QuestDB with 724 added lines and 321 deleted. This has been my biggest accepted opensource PR so far!

Projects: For more projects please view my portfolio website and or my github. My website covers my learning experience and showcases how I solved these projects. I have listed one of my favorites below.

NPC Loader

- Minecraft server/client based plugin with 170,000 plus downloads on spigot.
- The plugin allows for custom NPCs to be loaded into the Minecraft game. Configuration files created upon plugin usage, saving NPC location upon server close, customizable messages, naming NPCs, and deleting NPCs.
- GitHub: https://github.com/DLaMott/Npc

WORK EXPERIENCE

IAM Software engineer, Northwestern Mutual

Remote • May 2022 - Present

- Created a springboot microservice responsible for the provisioning of over 30,000+ users. The microservice is built utilizing java and maintains user provisioning by receiving updates on users throughout rest api endpoints within a secure server. The microservice maintains a secure AWS Aurora database following microservices best practices.
- Created two apache kafka consumer microservices to process and manage kafka business events allowing put and post requests towards a provisioning microservice. This allowed the business to move towards a non legacy application that utilized MO services.
- Assisted in creating ideal CI/CD pipelines allowing automated build, code quality scanning, and deployments to test, qa, and production environments.
- Became the acting DevOps Practioner as well as the primary Java developer for our team.
- Technologies used: AWS, Apache, Spring, Docker, Terraform, Node.js, Kubernetes, Java, Git, Gitlab, Gradle, Cyberark, MSK, Kafka, Kevlar, Cucumber, and SNOW.

Production Planner 1, Brakebush

Remote • January 2020 - May 2022

- Maintained product inventories and analyzed sale data to decide business needs.
- Worked with upper management and team to plan production for three facilities in the USA.
- Worked with logistics, procurement, and sales to manage product inventories and better plan production schedules.

Production Lead, Brakebush

Remote • August 2019 — January 2020

- Lead over 80 plus employees.
- Created and followed daily business plans.
- Ensured proper data recording in infinity and SAP applications.

Manager, Tar Heel Capital

Mocksville, NC • May 2015 — August 2019

- Created income and expense reports.
- Oversaw employees and ensured the team completed proper daily and nightly business activities.
- Analyzed sale data and reported to a superior manager to implement strategies.